[music]
Hi, I'm Ryan Dahl. You might know me as
the creator of Node.js.
As a programmer, I like things that are simple.
Really simple.
Programming should be simple.
That's why I created Node.
But these days Node is not simple.
[siren]
Just ask Rachel, she's been here for days.
Setting up TypeScript is an easy 47 step process:
first you take a TS config file [...] add an ES in front [...]
becomes a JavaScript target [...] don't forget Al Gore!
And here's Steve commemorating the 20th test
framework he's recently learned.
Ahh, please be gentle!
Okay, I'm good.
Getting Node APIs to work in the
browser can be...
...frustrating.
[crying]
Security is also a nightmare.
npm packages have access to everything.
Go, go, go! Grab everything, grab everything! Oh hey there!
But you can be a faster, more productive developer with Deno,
the simplest way to program.
Deno comes with TypeScript,
all-in-one tooling, and web
standard APIs, so you can write
once and run anywhere.
Anywhere?
Anywhere.
Deno is secure by default so every
dependency doesn't have full access to your computer.
[whoosh and shattering glass]
And you don't have to give
up the packages you love from npm.
I can use Next.js?
Yeah!
He said I can use Next.js!
And many more.
So join hundreds of thousands of developers using Deno
because programming should be simple.